Finding aid for the Doris D. Hall Collection of Travel and Recreation Ephemera and La Dow Family Documents LSC.1936
UCLA Library Special Collections
Doris D. Hall collection of travel and recreation ephemera and La Dow family documents
1877-1982
UCLA Library Special Collections
Hall, Doris D.
LSC.1936
1.0 linear feet (2 boxes)
Doris D. Hall was a resident of Los Angeles, California. This collection consists of printed materials related to travel and recreation within California and the greater U.S., ephemera, and home entertainment products of the 1930s-1980s. Also included are the La Dow Family papers which consist of legal documents.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift from Doris D. Hall, July 24, 1999.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9969526353606533
Biography/History
A native of Los Angeles, Doris D. Hall (1912-2011) was born Doris Marie D'Ooge and grew up in Inglewood. Her mother Josephine D'Dooge (née Wright) was from Massachusetts and her father was from Michigan. Doris married Harvey R. Hall (1905-1998) and they lived in the city of Los Angeles throughout their lives.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of printed materials related to travel and recreation within California and the greater U.S., including such items as maps, travel guides and menus, as well as ephemera, and home entertainment products of the 1930s-1980s. Also included are the La Dow Family papers which consist of legal documents. The connection between the Hall family and the La Dow documents isn't clear.
Hall, Doris D.
- Williams Pacific Tourist Guide, 1877 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Travel guide on the Union and Central Pacific railroad includes descriptions of railroad routes and points of interest.
- The Century Illustrated Monthly Magazine, vol. XLVII, no. 1, 1893 November (Box 1, Folder 2)
- California and Los Angeles Recreation, Ca. 1950-1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Booklet on Inglewood events, pamphlets on the El Camino Real Bell, Old Los Angeles, and Hotel Franciscan in San Francisco, guide to Los Angeles area recreation, map of El Pueblo de Los Angeles State Park, and a copy of the Centenial Edition of "California Highways and Public Works" (vol. 29, nos. 9,10).
- Menus, Ca. 1930s (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Menus from "Aladdin Studio Tiffin" in San Francisco and "Gestith Restaurant."
- Maps of California and U.S., Ca. 1940s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Thomas Guide Street Atlas, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Pamphlets and publications, Ca. 1920s-1970s (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Includes copy of "Etiquette, Entertaining and Good Sense," assorted pamphlets on sermons, how to be a succesful teacher, what to say in a rental ad. Also guides for gas and energy use.
- Ephemera, Ca. 1940-1963 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Old business cards, membership card for California Congress of Parents and Teachers, Inc., timetables and itinerary for Union Pacific trip.
- Product information guides for "Sound Products", Ca. 1937 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  "Sound Products" was based in Hollywood, California.
- Home entertainment equipment publications and clippings, Ca. 1930s-1980s (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Includes manuals, mailers, a 1978 issue of Popular electronics and materials on Splitdorf radios, Metzner turntables, Western Electric Switch Mate, and Bell and Howell 16mm projectors.
- Issue of Los Angeles Times "West" magazine, 1967 March 19 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- La Dow family papers, 1903-1959 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Includes a corporation dead, estate documents and chiropractic licenses.